Guide to the William Roy Kellough papers, 1979-1985.
Kellough, William Roy papers, 1979-1985.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
William Roy Kellough papers, 1979-1985.
3521
William Roy Kellough, 1923-
3.1 cubic ft.
Reports, lectures and speeches, articles, pamphlets and books, correspondence, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Reports, lectures and speeches, articles, pamphlets and books concerning Kellough's career as a land economist.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
W. R.Kellough became a member of the Ely Chapter of Lambda Alpha International in 1965, one of three of the first members from outside the continental United States. In 1967, he formed the first International chapter in Toronto Canada, the Simcoe Chapter, and was its first president. He was editor of the Land Economics Journal for a number of years and was International President for 1982-1983. He heads W.R. Kellough & Associates (Canada) Inc., appraisers and business and real estate economists.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Reports, lectures and speeches, articles, pamphlets and books concerning city and regional planning, real estate valuation, and other aspects of real estate development and land use; includes material concerning several areas of Ontario, Canada. Also includes miscellaneous papers and correspondence of Lambda Alpha, 1971-1982 (3 v.); correspondence and articles for preparation of the Land Economics Journal (2 v.); minutes and correspondence of the Simcoe chapter (1 v.); correspondence and data on the Comparative Study of the U.S. and Canadian Cities (1 v.); curricula vitae of new members and correspondence relating to the formation of the St. Louis, Phoenix, and Oklahoma Chapters; correspondence and other material of the International President, 1982-1983, and one volume of committee records for that period; and Lambda Alpha International Donors and Archives Content Cornell University Archives, a guide to the collections, compiled by Kellough.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kellough, William Roy, 1923-; Lambda Alpha International. Simcoe Chapter.; Lambda Alpha International. Oklahoma Chapter.; Lambda Alpha International. Phoenix Chapter.; Lambda Alpha International. St. Louis Chapter.
Subjects:
City planning.; City planning--Ontario.; Land use--Planning.; Real estate development.; Real property surveys.; Real property--Valuation.; Regional planning.; Regional planning--Canada.; Land economics.
Form and Genre Terms:
Curricula vitae.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to reports restricted for two years from receipt of same by the department.
RELATED MATERIALS
Part of Lambda Alpha Literary Archives.
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, articles, and legal documents, 1978-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Appraisals
  - Part Lot 2, Concession 2, City of St. Catharines for Chappell, Bushell & Stewart, Barristers & Solicitors, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Lots 22 & 23, Concession 4, WHS, Town of Caledon for Mazzard Enterprises Limited, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Part E 1/2 Lot 14, Concession 2, EHS, City of Brampton for Best & Gray, Barristers & Solicitors, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Century City Report No. 13, Part Lot 1, Concession 1, Town of Uxbridge, Files #9842, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Century City Report 14, Part Lots 1 & 2, Concession 1, Town of Uxbridge, File #9894, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Century City Report No. 15, Part Lot 1, Concession 1, Town of Uxbridge, File #9895, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Century City Report No. 16, Part Lot 1, Concession 1, Town of Uxbridge, File #9896, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Century City Report No. 17, Part Lot 1, Concession 1, Town of Uxbridge, File #9897, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Century City Report No. 18, Part Lot 1, Concession 1, File #9898, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Century City Report No. 19, Part Lot 1, Concession 1, Town of Uxbridge, File #9899, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Century City Report No. 20, Part Lot 1, Concession 1, Town of Uxbridge, File #9900, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Century City Report No. 22, Part Lot 1, Concession 1, Town of Uxbridge, File #9902, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Century City Report No. 23, Part Lot 1, Concession 2, Town of Uxbridge, File #9903, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Century City Report No. 24, Part Lot 4, Concession 2, Town of Uxbridge, File #9904, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Century City Report No. 25, Part Lot 4, Concession 2, Township of Uxbridge, File #9913, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Century City Report No. 26, Part Lot 3, Concession 2, Township of Uxbridge, File #9931, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Century City Report No. 27, Part Lot 30, Concession 9, Township of Pickering, File #9932, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Century City Report No. 3, Part Lots 23 & 24, Concession 9, Township of Pickering, File #9452, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Century City Report No. 4, Part Lot 5, Concession 2, Township of Uxbridge, File #9489, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Century City Report No. 5, Lot 4, Concession 2, Township of Uxbridge, File #9490, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Century City Report No. 6, Part Lot 3, Concession 2, Township of Uxbridge, File #9491, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Century City Report No. 1, Part Lot 32, Concession 9, File #9449, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Century City Report No. 2, Part Lot 30, Concession 9, Township of Pickering, File #9450, 1975 (Box 1)
  - The Midland Marina Project, ca. 1978 (Box 2)
  - 235 Belfield Road, Etobicoke, and 118 Dunkirk Road, St. Catherines for Peel Garden Investments Ltd., 1976 (Box 2)
  - A Preliminary Report Concerning Part of the West Half of Lot 12, Concession 3, EHS, City of Mississauga (formerly Township of Toronto), Ronald E. Dunn Property for Beatty, Bowyer, Greenslade & Hall, Barristers & Solicitors, 1976 (Box 2)
  - A Preliminary Report occasioned by a partial taking of Chaparral Developments Land Ltd., 1976 (Box 2)
  - Economic Analysis of the City of Guelph: Areal Economics - Industrial Analysis - Housing Market - Demographic Analysis - Residential Land Market, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Property Sales Data for the Township of Albion, the Town of Ajax, the Town of Aurora, the City of Barrie, the City of Belleville, the Town of Bolton, the Town of Brampton, the Township of Brighton, the Town of Burlington, the Township of Caledon East, the Township of Cartwright, the Township of Chinguacousy, the Township of Clarke, the Township of Darlington, the Township of East Gwillumbury, the Borough of East York, the Borough of Etobicoke, the Borough of Forest Hill, the Township of Georgina, the City of Guelph, the City of Hamilton, the Township of King, the Township of Kingston (Ontario, Canada) (Box 2)
  - Part of Lot 28, Concession 3, Town of Pickering, Alice Wood Property, for The Ministry of Housing, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Part Lot 30, Concession 9, Town of Markham, for Chappell, Bushell & Stewart, Barristers & Solicitors, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Business Investigation and Appraisal of: A Service Station, East Side of Markham Road at Milner Avenue, Borough of Scarborough, for Borough of Scarborough, 1976 (Box 2)
  - East Side of Markham Road at Milner Ave., Borough of Scarborough, for The Borough of Scarborough, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Part of Lot 28, Concession 3, Town of Pickering, George Wood Property, for Ministry of Housing, 1976 (Box 2)
  - 607 Mississauga Crescent, Town of Mississauga, for Outerbridge, Manning & Mueller, Barristers & Solicitors, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Century City Report No. 11, Part Lots 3 & 4, Concession 1, Township of Uxbridge, File #9497, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Century City Report No. 12, Part Lots 4 & 5, Concession 1, Township of Uxbridge, File #9498, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Century City Report No. 7, Part Lot 3, Concession 2, Township of Uxbridge, File #9492, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Century City Report No. 8, Part Lot 2, Concession 2, Township of Uxbridge, File #9493, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Century City Report No. 9, Part Lot 1, Concession 2, Township of Uxbridge, File #9495, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Century City Report No. 10, Part Lots 2 & 3, Concession 1, Township of Uxbridge, File #9496, 1975 (Box 2)
- Capitalization in the Appraisal Process, May 1963 (Box 2)
- Rent Inflation and Its Implications, 1967 (Box 2)
- Anatomy of the Housing Shortage: Four Essays in Urban Economics, Mar. 1969 (Box 2)
- Farm Equipment: Promise, Performance and Standards: Submission to the Royal Commission on Farm Machinery (Box 2)
- Land Economic Analysis of Farm Sales or the Finding of Value from Price (Box 2)
- Correspondence, 1981 (Box 2)
- Articles and essays (Box 2)
- Lambda Alpha - 1983 Congress - Papers of International President - W.R. Kellough, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
- Formation of Hawaii Chapter by W.R. Kellough, International President, ca. 1982-1984 (Box 3)
- Chartering of the Oklahoma Chapter, ca. 1982-1984 (Box 3)
- Chartering of the St. Louis Chapter, ca. 1982-1984 (Box 3)
- Formation of the Florida Chapter by W.R. Kellough, International President, ca. 1982-1983 (Box 3)
- Chartering of the Phoenix Chapter, ca. 1983-1984 (Box 3)
- Correspondence, 1981 (Box 3)
- Lambda Alpha International, Donors and Archives Content, Cornell University Archives, Apr. 1984 (Box 3)
- Lambda Alpha International Board of Governors and Executive Meetings, 1980-1983 (Box 3)
- Market Study and Impact Analysis, Town of Ajax, 1985 (Box 4)
- Presidential Correspondence - Lambda Alpha, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Volume 1)
- Presidential Correspondence - Lambda Alpha, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Volume 2)
- Presidential Correspondence - Lambda Alpha, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Volume 3)
- Lambda Alpha Land Economics Journal - Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Volume 1)
- Lambda Alpha Land Economics Journal - Correspondence, 1977-1986 (Box 5, Volume 2)
- Lambda Alpha Land Economics Journal, 1981 (Box 5, Volume 3)
- Lambda Alpha - Correspondence, 1971-1975 (Box 5)
- Lambda Alpha - Correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 5)
- Lambda Alpha - Simcoe Chapter, 1971-1982 (Box 5)
- International Fraternity of Lambda Alpha - Committees - W.R. Kellough, President, 1982-1983 (Box 5)
- Lambda Alpha Committee for a Comparative Study of Major U.S. and Canadian Cities, 1977-1980 (Box 5)